Are you kidding me?
너무 징헌 거 아니냐?
Joey?
조이? 조이! 조이! 조이!
조이! 조이! 조이! 조이!
조이, 조이, 조이!
오호라, 나 땜에 깨셨어?
Did I wake you?
The One with
All the Wedding Dresses
커피 한 잔 더 할까요?
Gunther, could I get
another cup of coffee?
So what do you do when
you're not working here?
쉬는 날엔 뭘 하면서 지내죠?
-You don't need to fill these silences.
-Okay, thanks.
- 억지로 말 붙일 거 없어
- 네, 고마워요
That's your fourth cup of coffee.
챈들러, 벌써 네 잔 째 아냐?
좋아, 내 것도 맞혀봐
Okay, do me.
I've had a certain number of juices.
나는 얼마만큼의
주스를 마셨을까?
너무 피곤해서 마시는 거야
조이가 코를 골기 시작했어
I'm exhausted because
Joey started snoring.
He's in a different room.
He's that loud?
같은 방도 아닌데
그렇게 시끄러워?
맛을 아직 못 봤구나
You should hear me.
It's nothing to be proud of.
Go to a sleep clinic.
그게 무슨 자랑이냐?
수면장애클리닉에 가봐
얘기했잖아
그런 데는 안 가
I'm not going to any clinic.
I don't have a problem.
You have the problem.
난 말짱해
문제는 너한테 있어
You should go to a "Quit-being-
a-baby-and-leave-me-alone" clinic.
'만성 참견증 투덜이'
클리닉에나 가봐
-They don't have those.
-Yeah, they do.
그런 게 어디 있냐
있대두, 상습적으로
참견하는 투덜아
Quit being a baby and leave me alone!
There, you just had your first class.
댁은 그거부터 치료하세요
I used to date a light sleeper.
잠귀 밝은 남자랑
사귄 적이 있는데
Whenever I snored,
he rolled me over
- 코를 골면 날 뒤집었어
- 오, 예...
Oh, yeah!
He'd roll me over,
and I'd stop snoring.
돌아누우면
코고는 걸 멈추니까
너 또 코골면
내가 뒤집어주겠어
Next time you snore,
I'm rolling you over!
I gotta do what I gotta do.
You gotta do what you gotta do.
난 나대로 살고
넌 너대로 살고, 맘대로 해
Hey, guys.
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
딴딴다단 딴딴다단...
아, 올림픽 찬가
Oh, the Olympics!
-Have you picked a date?
-No. Not yet.
결혼날짜 잡았어?
아니, 아직
로스가 결혼을 하게 되다니
I still cannot believe
you're engaged.
Because it's so fast.
Not because you're a loser.
갑작스럽다는 뜻이지
네가 푼수라는 게 아냐
Thanks. Has anyone seen Rach?
고맙다, 누가 레이첼 봤니?
집에서 놀면서 설거지도 안 해
She's upstairs not doing the dishes.
이번엔 가만두고 지켜볼 거야
I won't do them this time.
Even if they sit there until....
곰팡이가 덕지덕지 피든 말든...
가자마자 바로 설거지해야겠다
I'll do them when I get home.
그리고 에밀리가 런던에서
웨딩드레스를 골랐거든
Emily found this
wedding dress in London
벌써?
-Already?
-But it didn't fit.
근데 맞지가 않아, 다행히 여기
매장에 맞는 게 한 벌 있지만
There's a store here with one left in her size.
But the groom can't see
- 신랑은 드레스를 못 보니까...
- 내가 찾아올게
-I'll pick it up for you.
-Thanks.
- 고마워
- 그래
벌써부터 신랑 될 사람한테
그런 심부름이나 시키고...
She's got you running errands,
picking up wedding dresses....
Wah-pah!
와파!
What's wah-pah?
와파가 뭐야
You know. Whipped.
알잖아, 채찍소리
Wah-pah!
와파!
That's not whipped.
그게 무슨 채찍소리냐
Whipped is....
채찍소리는 후키시!
That's what I did.
나도 그렇게 했잖아
와파!
You can't do anything!
어떻게 제대로 하는 게 없냐
Hey, Mon.
I was just doing these dishes.
어서 와, 모니카
- 설거지 좀 하느라고...
- 나야
너구나, 왔어?
Do you have a minute?
시간 좀 있어?
안 그래도 쉬려던 참이야
I was just about to
take a break anyway.
So listen...
있잖아
...I know we haven't had
a chance to talk...
내가 결혼 발표한 이후로는
우리 제대로 얘기를 못했지?
...since Emily and l
decided to get married.
And I was just wondering
how you were.
괜찮은지 궁금해서
만약 네가 결혼한다면
난 아마 기분이...
If you were getting married,
I would feel kind of....
You know?
- 알지?
- 그럼
It definitely took me by surprise.
But, you know...
많이 놀란 건 사실이지만...
...I'm okay.
난 괜찮아
- 그래?
- 응, 정말 괜찮아
I just wanted to check.
- 난 혹시나 해서
- 자상도 하시지, 고마워
That's sweet. Thank you.
You're great.
넌 멋진 여자야, 네게도
곧 좋은 일이 생길 거야
And I know someday this will
happen for you too.
You just hang in there.
조금만 참고 견뎌
"Hang in there"?
참고 견뎌?
No, I didn't mean....
아니, 내 말은...
나와 조슈아 사이에 뜨끈한
기류가 감돈다는 말이 있던데
You haven't heard of a serious
relationship called "me and Joshua"?
겨우 네 번 만났다고 해서
별 진전이 없는 줄 알았지
I thought you had
just been on four dates.
I didn't realize that had
become anything.
아냐, 무슨 소리
진전 엄청 많아
Oh no, it has become.
Oh no, those were four great dates.
네 번 다 불같은 만남이었거든
- 정말?
- 그럼
I mean, and the connection!
찰떡궁합이라고나 할까?
Emotionally, mentally.
You know?
감정적으로나
정신적으로나
Physically.
속궁합까지...
-That's incredible.
-I know, isn't it?
- 와, 정말 잘됐다
- 그렇지?
I'm right there with Joshua.
You are right there with Emily.
난 조슈아가 있고
넌 에밀리가 있고
And it's kind of like it's a tie.
우린 뭐랄까...
동점이지
I gotta get back to my dishes.
설거지 마저 해야겠다
- 나도 일하러 가야지
- 그래, 가봐
I gotta get to work.
You know what would
make me happy?
내게 좋은 생각이 있어
You know, what's that?
그래? 뭔데?
If the four of us could all,
you know, hang out together.
우리 넷이 한번
만나는 게 어떨까
Emily's coming into
town this weekend.
이번 주말에 에밀리도 오니까
저녁이나 같이 해, 일요일쯤
Why don't we all
have dinner Sunday night?
That would be great!
- 그거 좋겠다
- 괜찮아?
All right. It's a date!
- 그럼 약속한 거야
- 좋아
"Hang in there."
You hang in there.
참고 견뎌?
댁이나 잘하셔
-Did you say something?
-No, just singing.
- 방금 뭐라고 했어?
- 아니, 노래 불렀어
베아트리체 웨딩샵
Oh, my God!
어머나, 세상에
Look at this one!
이것 좀 봐
It's so beautiful.
너무 예쁘다
그래
About half of these will
end up getting divorced.
이 중에 절반이 이혼한대
May I help you ladies?
도와드릴까요?
I'm here to pick up a dress on hold.
네, 드레스 찾으러 왔는데요
What's the name?
성함이 어떻게 되시죠?
-Emily Waltham.
-Yes, I have it right here.
에밀리 월섬
이쪽에 준비해뒀습니다
세상에
Would you like to try it on,
Miss Waltham?
한번 입어보시겠어요, 월섬 양?
좋아요
You're the most beautiful bride
I've ever seen.
이렇게 예쁜 신부는 처음이다
I am, aren't l?
- 진짜다, 그치?
- 음
Miss Waltham?
월섬 양
네
We're closing.
문 닫을 시간이에요
All right.
알았어요
And could I get my ring back?
제 반지는 주셔야죠?
All right, buddy.
Time to roll over.
좋다, 임마
뒤집기 시간이다
안돼! 이런 흉측한 놈!
You are going to a clinic!
You're going to a clinic!
당장 클리닉에 가자
클리닉에 갔다가...
And a pajama store!
파자마 가게도 들르자
Does she use the cups?
레이첼은 컵을 안 쓰나요?
안 쓰긴요, 잘만 쓰죠
Yes, I believe she does.
Does she use the plates?
Yes, I believe she does!
레이첼은 접시를 안 쓰나요?
무슨 말씀, 잘만 써요
Thank you.
고맙습니다
Thank you very much.
대단히 감사합니다
Thank you for coming.
와주셔서 감사해요
-Just a second.
-No, no! Let me in!
- 잠깐만요
- 안돼, 빨랑 문 열어
- 피비?
- 그래
Can you hold on a minute?
잠깐만 기다릴래?
No! You have to
let me in right now!
안돼, 당장 문 열라니까
Are you alone?
- 너 혼자 있니?
- 그래
All right.
알았어
This sucks.
돌겠다
I have to stay up all night
before I go to the stupid clinic.
진찰 받으려면 전날 밤에
한숨도 자면 안 된다잖아
I'm so tired.
사람 잡겠네
It's six o'clock.
이제 6시야
얘들아
I hear you and Joshua are
going out with Ross and Emily.
넷이서 저녁 먹기로 했다며?
아주 잘 생각한 거야
I think that's really cool.
맞아, 잘 대처하고 있어
I think you're handling
that really well.
"Handling it"?
대처해?
There's nothing to handle.
뭘 대처한다는 거야
Maybe I'd have a problem with this
if it wasn't for me and Joshua.
조슈아가 없었더라면
문제가 됐을지도 모르지
They're not going to
get married anyway.
어쨌든 두 사람은 결혼 안 해
뭐?
They rushed into this thing
so fast, it's ridiculous!
생각해봐, 두 사람 너무
경솔하다는 느낌 안 들어?
약혼기간이 얼마나 될까
한 1년?
They'll be engaged for like what?
A year?
그 사이에 둘 중 누군가가
정신을 차리고 그만두겠지
One of them will realize
what they've done...
...and call it off.
You'll be dancing at my wedding
before you dance at theirs.
두고 봐, 내 결혼식장에서
먼저 춤을 추게 될 걸?
You know, I don't dance at weddings.
난 결혼식 가서 춤 안 춰
Why not?
왜?
Weddings are a great place
to meet women.
식장엔 여자들도 많이 오는데
춤을 추면 난 이 꼴이 되거든
When I dance, I look like this.
Hey, man.
- 나야
- 그래
What are you doing
four weeks from today?
너희들 4주 후에
다른 계획 있어?
- 전혀
- 나도
-Nothing.
이 몸은...
I am...
...free.
한가하다
Because we're getting
married in a month.
다행이다, 에밀리와 난
한 달 후에 결혼할 거야
-What?
-Yes.
뭐?
넵
In a month?
- 한 달 후에?
- 그래
- 30일 후라고?
- 그럼
-You mean 30 days?
-Yeah.
From now?
- 오늘부터 따져서?
- 맞아
That's great!
- 잘됐다!
- 그렇지?
에밀리 부모님들이 식을 올렸던
멋진 건물이 곧 헐린다는 거야
She always wanted to get married
where her parents did...
...but it's getting torn down.
해서 미친 짓인 줄 알지만
우린 처음부터 그랬잖아
I know it's crazy,
but everything's been so crazy...
...and it just feels right.
순리대로 가는 거지 뭐
Hey, that's the day after
I start menstruating!
어라? 나 생리 시작한
다음날이네
This isn't mine.
내 게 아니구나
-Hey, Rachel.
-Hi.
- 레이첼
- 왔군요
What's up?
무슨 일이죠?
Your voice sounded
all squeaky on the phone.
전화 목소리는
다급한 것 같던데
아뇨, 그냥 보고 싶어서
Nothing.
I just wanted to see you.
See you and hug you.
보고 껴안고...
See you....
또 보고...
Great!
- 잘했어요
- 네, 그니까...
Sit.
착석!
You okay?
괜찮아요?
I'm more than okay.
I am really, really happy.
괜찮은 정도가 아니죠
졸도할 만큼 행복하니까
Want to know why?
왠지 알아요?
Do l?
왜일까?
Because I am really happy about us.
우리를 생각하면 행복해요
I think we are so
on the right track.
제대로 좍좍 풀리고 있잖아요
기계 돌아가듯 착착 들어맞고
I think we are working.
I think we are clicking.
-You know?
-Yeah, sure, sure.
- 알아요?
- 무, 물론 착착 맞죠
We're clicking.
네, 근데 우리 사이에
아쉬운 부분이 있다면
If there was just
one little area where...
...I think we need to work on,
I would think...
정열이 부족하다는 거예요
...it's that we're
just not crazy enough.
I got to say, I'm not too sure
I agree with that.
글쎄, 동의하긴 좀 힘든데
You know, yeah, you're right.
그래요, 당신 말도 옳아요
우리도 나름대로는 즐겁죠
We have our fun. Yeah?
하지만 이건...
왜 있잖아요
꼭지 화악! 도는 거
I mean, like crazy!
You know?
Are you gonna put on
that cheerleader outfit again?
그 치어리더복장
또 입으려구요?
아니에요
No. You wish.
엉큼하시긴
네, 좋아요
All right.
This is going to sound, you know,
a little hasty.
약간은 경솔하게
들릴지 모르지만
But just go with me.
그냥 밀어붙일게요
What if we got married?
우리 결혼하는 게 어때요?
-What?
-Oh, I know. It's so totally like...
네?
알아요, 이런 생각이 들겠죠
'와! 그래도 되나?', 그치만...
..."Whoa, can we do this?"
You know?
But it just feels right.
Don't you think it does?
이건 필연 같아요, 그렇죠?
확신이 들어요, 안... 그래요?
I mean, it just feels right.
Don't you...?
Rachel...
레이첼...
...you're...
당신은...
...a real...
정말이지...
...special lady.
특별한 여자랍니다
하지만 난 이혼소송 중이고
우린 겨우 네 번 만났어요
But my divorce isn't final yet...
...and we've been on four dates.
So I'm thinking: No...
나로선 아무래도
안 된다 싶지만
...but...
어쨌든...
고마워요
...thanks.
You idiot!
이런 밥통아!
-Your name, please?
-Joey Tribbiani.
성함은요?
조이 트리비아니
Did you stay up all night
in preparation for your study?
말씀드린 대로
밤새 안 주무셨겠죠?
선생님?
Sir?
Yes, he did.
네, 안 잤어요
좋습니다
잠시만 기다리세요
All right. We'll call you
in a few minutes.
Check out that girl.
She's really hot.
저 여자 좀 봐
쭉쭉빵빵이다
Yeah, she is.
그래, 좋다
와아...
How you doing?
안녕하쇼
You looking good.
빼어난 미모십니다
-What?
-You're coming on to the entire room.
왜?
이 방 사람들 다 엮을래?
-I'm Chandler.
-I'm Marjorie.
- 전 챈들러랍니다
- 마저리예요
- 반갑습니다
- 안녕하세요
-Do you mind if I sit?
-Please.
- 앉아도 될까요?
- 네, 그러세요
So what are you in for?
무슨 일로 오셨어요?
I talk in my sleep.
잠꼬대가 심하거든요
What a coincidence!
I listen in my sleep.
저런, 난 자면서
얘길 들어주는데
So why don't you give me your number?
연락처나 좀 주쇼
- 준비됐어?
- 그래
Are you ready?
좋아
I got it! Mine!
잡았다, 내 거야!
-Congratulations!
-Thank you!
- 축하해
- 고마워
- 이제 내 차례야
- 알았어
My turn, my turn!
Okay, ready?
자, 준비
됐다
That was a terrible throw!
그것밖에 못 던져?
너한테 던지면
가짜 같잖아
I won't throw it right to you.
That's not real.
Look at me. My big concern
is what's real?
날 봐, 진짜가짜
따지게 생겼어?
Oh, my God!
맙소사
We're really sad, aren't we?
이게 웬 청승이니
Yeah, I think we are.
그래, 맞다
This isn't even my dress.
내 드레스도 아닌데
At least you didn't rent yours from
a store called "It's Not Too Late."
그래도 넌 '아직 늦지 않았다'
코너에서 빌리진 않았잖아
-I'm changing out of this.
-Me, too.
- 갈아입어야겠다
- 나도
In half an hour?
- 30분만 더 있다가?
- 나도
Me, too.
- 좋아, 이번엔 잘 던져
- 알았어
All right, now throw it
straight this time.
그래
I'm getting married!
나도 시집간다!
I hate my regular clothes now.
이제 평상복은 싫다 얘
알아?
I look down and I know...
이걸 보면 오늘하루가
너무 따분할 것 같아
...this won't be the most
special day of my life.
그래, 잠깐은 재미있었지만
진짜 바보 같은 짓이었지?
I mean, it was kind of
fun for a while...
...but didn't you feel kind of silly?
I guess.
그래
Oh, my God!
엄마야!
이런 앙큼한 것 같으니
You're such a cheater!
Hello, little ones.
안녕, 아가씨들?
- 어서 와
- 안녕
-So, is Joey going to stop snoring?
-Yep!
조이는 치료된대?
그럼, 게다가 난
예쁜 여자를 만났지
And a beautiful woman
agreed to go out with me.
Joey wanted to ask her out,
but, you know, she picked me.
조이도 접근했지만
그 여자가 날 찍었어
어떻게 그럴 수가 있어?
How'd that happen?
Because I'm cooler.
내가 더 멋지니까
No, seriously.
장난하지 말고
She's the kind of girl....
Joey was unconscious.
뭐냐, 그 여자 취향이...
조이가 의식불명이었어
Hey, you guys!
What's happening?
얘들아, 뭐하냐?
Oh, my God!
맙소사
What is that?
그게 뭐야?
They gave it to me
at the sleep clinic...
수면장애클리닉에서 준 건데
이러고 있으면 코를 안 곤대
...and it's going to help me
not to snore.
Well, are you asleep right now, Joe?
너 지금 수면 중이니?
You don't have to
wear it unless you are.
자는 게 아니면 빼도 되잖아
I know I don't have to.
그건 나도 알지만...
It tastes good.
맛있어
Plus, you look cool.
보기에도 근사하다
Hope I didn't stretch Emily's dress.
드레스 늘어났을까 걱정이다
Your butt's not
that much bigger than her's.
엉덩이 사이즈는
비까비까한데 뭐
I just called Joshua.
방금 조슈아한테 전화했어
How'd it go?
어떻게 됐어?
I did my best to
convince him that I'm not...
난 결혼 못해 안달 난 여자가
아니라고 입 아프게 설명했지
...some crazy girl who's
dying to get married.
And I'm going through
a hard time.
나도 힘들다고
What'd he say?
뭐래?
His answering machine
was very understanding.
글쎄, 자동응답기라
잘 들어주긴 하더라
I feel blue.
정말 비참하다
꼭 다시 전화해줄 거야
I bet you anything
he'll call you again.
Yeah, maybe. But, you know,
I don't think I even care.
하지만 이제 그건 상관없어
I don't think he's
the one I'm sad about.
그 사람 때문에
우울한 게 아닌가 봐
로스가 결혼해도
난 괜찮다고 했지만
I know I said I'm totally okay
with Ross getting married.
But as it turns out...
지금 보니까 그 문제를
감당하기 힘든 것 같아
...I don't think I'm handling it
all that well.
Yeah, maybe.
그렇게 보인다
And I'm just trying to
figure out why.
이유를 곰곰이 생각해봤어
Any luck?
결론은?
You know how Ross and I have
always been on-again, off-again?
로스와 난 걸핏하면 연결됐다
깨지고 연결됐다 깨지고...
I guess I just figured,
somewhere down the road...
언젠가 다시 잘될 거라는
믿음이 있었나 봐
...we would be on again.
Again.
다시...
You know what?
I think we all did.
우리 모두 그렇게 믿었어
- 나야
- 왔어?
저녁 먹을 식당 잡았어
어니스에서 9시 어때
I got us reservations
for Sunday night.
How about Ernie's at 9:00?
Well, you'd better make it for three.
셋이 하는 게 좋겠어
I don't know if we're
going to be hungry at three.
글쎄, 3시에 배가 고플까?
Three people.
세 명만 모이자고
조슈아는 안 올 거야
Joshua's not going to be there.
What happened?
무슨 일 있어?
우리 끝난 거 같아
Well, I think he broke up with me.
No. Why?
저런, 왜?
Apparently, he scares easy.
겁이 좀 많더라
Rachel, I'm sorry.
레이첼, 유감이다
아냐, 괜찮아
It's okay.
Sometimes things don't work out
the way you thought they would.
세상 일이 항상 내 맘처럼
풀리는 건 아니니까
Come here.
이리 와
Don't you have to go pick up Emily?
에밀리 마중 나가야지
- 그래
- 가봐
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. I got my girls.
괜찮아?
그럼, 듬직한 얘들이 있잖아
알았어
Hey, you know what might
cheer you up?
분위기 좀 띄워볼까?
What?
뭘로?
I got to tell you...
이거 쓸만하다
...this really does put me
in a better mood.
기분이 훨씬 좋아졌어
I wish there was a job where
I could wear this all the time.
종일 이것만 입고
일하는 직업 없을까?
Maybe someday there will be.
언젠가는 생기겠지
Chandler's coming by to borrow
candles for his big date.
이런, 챈들러가 여자친구
온다고 초를 빌려 달랬어
알았어
Rachel, don't get it!
He'll see us!
안돼, 레이첼
그러고 나갈 거야?
맞아, 신랑은 신부 보면 안돼
The groom cannot see the bride.
I'm not going to marry Chandler.
누가 챈들러랑 결혼한대?
Not after this!
보여주면 당연히 못하지
Okay guys, just relax.
됐어, 그냥 자연스럽게
I do!
맹세합니다...
I got to go.
갈게요
안돼요, 조슈아
조슈아...
Yeah, well, that ought to do it.
뭐 깨끗이 정리됐네
Food's here. Fair enough.
음식 나왔어요
아주 좋아요
Fifteen-minute warning.
15분 남았어요
Late.
나중에
Dude, I am trying to sleep!
야, 나도 잠 좀 자자